João Santos

Junior Software Engineer

Personal Info



+351 914 086 424



j-almeidasantos@hotmail.com



j-almeidasantos



isantos42



jsantos42.github.io/portfolio/



Lisbon, PT

[Natural] Languages

English	C2
French	B2
Spanish	B1
Portuguese	C2

[Programming] Languages

С	Good
C++	Confortable
Python	Confortable
R	Basic
Javascript	Confortable
React.js	Confortable
(HTML/CSS)	Confortable

Other Tools/Framworks

Git	Good
Unix Shell	Good
Shell Scripting	Confortable
GoogleTest	Intermediate
Agile (Scrum) & Jira	Confortable

With a background in Medicine, 6+ years of clinical practice, and having worked in two countries, I have always been fascinated by technology. Over the years, I grew tired of working with poorly-designed and non-intuitive software, and eventually took the decision to build better software for healthcare. My long-term goal is to help rebuilding our National Healthcare System software. For now, I'm willing to learn as much as I can, in any field that arouses my interest.

Experience

Jan 2022 present

Software Engineer Intern | Critical Techworks

- Working on BMW's cars' infotainment, developing the HMI* of the Navigation panel
- Maintaining the existing codebase (in **C++**)
- Adding new features and making Unit Tests
- Adding new UI with the QT framework
- *Human Machine Interface

Oct 2020 present

Programming Student | 42 Lisboa

- Working in individual and team projects
- Solving challenges in different programming languages, mainly in C and C++

Sep 2019 -Dec 2021

Student Researcher | Universidade de Lisboa

My Master's thesis in Clinical Nutrition involved:

- Geospatial data analysis using Python and R
- Making use of Jupiter notebook and geopandas

Jul 2018 -Jul 2021

Resident Doctor | ARSLVT (Lisbon)

Mar 2018 – Dec 2020

Medical Doctor | Hospital Santa Maria (Lisbon)

Oct 2014 -Jul 2016

Resident Doctor ("Externe") | AP-HP (Paris)

Education

Oct 2020 present

Software Engineering Course

42 Lisboa

Set 2018 -Dec 2021

Master's Degree in Clinical Nutrition

Universidade de Lisboa

Sep 2010 -Jul 2016

Doctor of Medicine

Universidade de Lisboa & Pierre et Marie Curie Université

Hobbies

Cycling Cooking Reading Learning Traveling Photography